What was that...?
Eh? Sure.
Kawachi
I just woke up.
Is that so?
I got it.
Don't worry about it.
I'll talk to them next Monday, okay?
See ya.
My grandpa from my mother's side passed away last night.
That dream just now, it was about Grandpa and... my mum?
My relatives and I seemed to have grown distant.
It's been a while since I've been here, and now I'm here but for a funeral.
Oyatsu Fansubs Presents
Usagi
Drop
ashita no koto ha wakannai
明日のことは　分かんない
We don't know what's going to happen tomorrow.
korette gisei toha chigau nanika ga chigau
これって　犠牲とは違う　何かが違う
This is different from sacrificing, very different.
batsugeemu jaa nante omou wa nai
罰ゲームじゃあ　なんて思うわない
I don't think this is a punishment game either.
tte nande nanoka ha wakannai
って　なんでなのかは　分かんない
I can't really say well what it is.
chotto shakuzen to shinai kedo
ちょっと　釈然としないけど
In fact, I do feel quite troubled,
kimi no sonzai ima daiji da nantemonjanai
キミの存在　今大事だ　なんてもんじゃない
but "important" cannot be used to describe your existence any more.
owaranai koto nante konoyo no dokonimonai
終わらないことなんて　この世のどこにもない
There's nothing that will last forever without coming to an end.
naku no ha tsurai janai no
泣くのは辛いじゃないの
Crying is a very painful thing
I know! Sweet drops! Sweet drops!
zutto yume mite itaine
ずっと　夢見ていたいね
I have always wanted to dream
motto yasashiku shitaine
もっと　優しくしたいね
To be able to be more gentle
kimi to iraretara happy!
キミと居られたら　happy!
Just being together with you is happy.
onnanoko tte tsuyoi ne
女の子って　強いね
Girls are strong,
dakedo tokitoki yowai ne
だけど　ときとき　弱いね
but at times, they are weak.
bokura no negai ha happy! happy! happy...
僕らの願いは　happy! happy! happy...
Our wish is to be happy! Happy! Happy!
sonna hibi mo happy!
そんな日々も happy!
Such happy days!
Just wanna make you happy...
I'm here.
Oh, it's Daiki-chan. You're pretty early.
Go put your baggage in Grandpa's bedroom.
Okay.
There's a little girl in the garden.
Since when did Haruko's kid look like that?
That isn't Reina-chan.
Then whose kid?
Jeez... I can't seem to get used to this kitchen.
How are we going to deal with this?
At the age of 79, he's lived long enough.
That girl seems to be your grandpa's illegitimate child.
WHAT?
Grandpa's kid?!
He didn't tell me anything about it.
That lover of his isn't even here anymore.
Lover?
He's already 79 years old, right?
What a disgrace.
That means, she's your sister?
Which also makes her my aunt.
How can you still pull a joke like that!
You're already in your thirties, don't say things without thinking!
Rest in peace, Grandpa.
How much should I give?
It's the thought that counts; how much you give doesn't matter.
That may be true, but there must be a rough estimate.
Any amount is fine, really.
But nowadays, the practice is to peg the sum according to both the ritual and posthumous name...
It should be around forty to fifty thousand.
That isn't cheap.
It's been a while.
Oh, Daikichi, long time no see.
Were you busy all this while?
Yeah, pretty much.
Busy as always.
Did you know Mum's always thinking of you?
You don't even come home during the New Year.
Here.
Reina, stop!
Wait, Reina!
Haruko.
Hey Dai-chan, haven't seen you in a while.
Mama~
Reina!
Now I've caught you.
Seriously, a good kid must always be obedient.
I don't want to!
What's wrong?
It's nothing.
You really have grown to resemble your grandpa.
Daikichi, you must have heard about it.
Yeah, my mum told me about it earlier.
Is that really true?
I understand it gets really lonely living by yourself...
There seems to be an MCH Handbook; I think her name is Rin.
Note: MCH Handbook = Maternal and Child Health Handbook (boshi techo). It is a handbook given to a mother when she registers her pregnancy in Japan.
But, speaking of which, doing such a thing when he's already 79.
Well, it'd be an exception if Dad was the one who did it.
But for it to happen to Grandpa, somehow I feel he did a great job.
Daikichi, help me bring out the cushions from the cupboard.
What are you doing?
Hey, exchange with me.
Don't do that, just give it to me that way.
I did it!
Hey, look at me.
Reina, I told you to stop running.
Wow, you're good.
It's beautiful, right?
Of course.
Reina-chan is really good at the Cat's Cradle.
Why not do a "4-step-ladder" next?
Oh my. Reina-chan, let me show you.
Poo bomb!
Stop that, Reina!
Uncle. Uncle.
You should go and sleep.
I'll keep watch on the incense.
Oh, I see.
Hey, don't sleep here.
Let's go inside and sleep.
What about the incense?
Daikichi said he will keep watch.
Come on, stand up.
I'm counting on you, bro.
Ah!
You should also sleep inside.
I'm all right.
You look horrible.
Kaga Souichi
Well then everyone, let's bid our final farewell.
Ask my mum how she's doing.
Brother...
Come over here, Reina.
Yes!
Say goodbye to Grandpa.
Okay.
Flowers~!
Don't do that!
No! I want to make a flower garden.
I want it!
You should come over and say goodbye too.
Place this beside Grandpa.
Hey!
Bellflower...
...Grandpa's favourite flower.
Grandpa likes this flower the most.
Won't he wake up any more?
Yeah, he won't even wake up.
You must really be Grandpa's daughter...
Where did this Yoshii Masako go?
Mother and Child Health Handbook
22nd November 2004
Parent Names
Child's name
Kaga Souichi
Yoshii Masako
Rin
Someone who abandoned her child and ran away;
I doubt anything will happen even if we manage to locate her.
Honestly, how irresponsible.
He's seriously very stubborn.
That's dangerous!
You know, that girl, she's unable to talk.
What a bother, her teeth haven't even dropped off yet.
She knows how to talk, what's bothersome about it.
No, she can't. That's why I'm so bored now!
Here, take them all and play somewhere else.
Looks like a candy shop, wow...
Sorry about that, Dai-chan.
Let's not talk that far ahead.
For now, who's going to look after that child?
I have to tend to my shop, so we can't do.
If only she's more normal, it'd be better.
She doesn't seem to be able to talk.
Mum, you've nothing better to do at home.
Why not let her stay there for the time being?
T-That's impossible. I'm not as free as you think.
Besides, do you know just how tough it is to raise a child?
Do you know, up till now, how many sacrifices I've made to raise both of you?
Also, if you don't do it well, she'll be the one who ends up suffering.
I thought everyone is discussing on who will look after Rin?
Besides, you don't intend to lend a hand anyway.
Let's face it, this is reality.
We also can't confirm whether she's really Grandpa's daughter.
Look, you can't even argue, because you don't think about what you say.
In any case, let's find some place where she will be accepted immediately.
W-What's with you?
Rin!
Wanna come to my place?
What are you saying, Daikichi?
Onii-chan!
I'm hungry, Uncle.
U-Uncle?
Don't call me Uncle!
No matter how you see it, you're my Aunt.
nichiyou no hare ta hiru sagari
日曜の晴れた昼さがり
On a clear Sunday afternoon
kyou ha doko he yukou
今日はどこへ行こう
Where are we heading today?
kayoi nareta itsumo no michi ga mabushiku kagayaite mieru
通い慣れたいつもの道が眩しく輝いて見える
The usual road that we always take seems to be shining radiantly
terasu atatakai taiyou to tonari ni kimi ga ireba
照らす暖かい太陽と　隣に君がいれば
The warm sun shining with you still by my side
mou High High High
もう　High　High　High
We're already high, high high
hashagidasu kimochi ni
はしゃぎだす気持ちに
Feeling merry
utae Life Life Life
歌え　Life　Life　Life
Sing life, life, life
koe ha dokomade mo
声はどこまでも
I can hear our voices anywhere
mou High High High
もう　High　High　High
We're already high, high, high
maiagaru kaze ni nori
舞い上がる風に乗り
Riding on the soaring wind
utae Life Life Life
歌え　Life　Life　Life
Sing life, life, life
koe mo tobihaneru
声も飛び跳ねる
Our voices are hopping too
Does it taste good?
Yes.
You want another bowl?
There aren't any more side dishes.
I can make them into rice balls.
There are also no matching ingredients for the rice balls.
Salt.
Salt?
Hey, that's still very hot.
Hey, watch it.
But it has a warm taste when you eat it.
Here you go, Uncle.
That's wrong. Daikichi.
Even Daikichi sounds weird...
It's delicious.